digitalartsonline.co.uk 2015-06-11

# T&C | IDG UK

## Introduction – who we are

This website is owned and operated by IDG Communications Limited of 101 Euston Road, London, NW1 2RA, United Kingdom, Reg. Co. No. 1197840, VAT No. GB-404696446 ("IDG UK").  IDG UK has notified as a data controller under the UK Data Protection Act 1998.

IDG UK is the owner and operator of CIO UK ([www.cio.co.uk](http://www.cio.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Techworld UK ([www.techworld.com](http://www.techworld.com/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Computerworld UK ([www.computerworlduk.com](http://www.computerworlduk.com/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), PC Advisor ([www.pcadvisor.co.uk](http://www.pcadvisor.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Macworld ([www.macworld.co.uk](http://www.macworld.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), MacVideo ([www.macvideo.tv](http://www.macvideo.tv/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Digital Arts Online ([www.digitalartsonline.co.uk](http://www.digitalartsonline.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Tech Advisor ([www.techadvisor.co.uk](http://www.techadvisor.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)), Tech-Resources ([www.tech-resources.co.uk](http://www.tech-resources.co.uk/?utm_content=web.archive.org)) and sub-domains of these websites. IDG UK is a subsidiary of International Data Group, Inc.

The International Data Group, Inc. (IDG) family of on-line and print publications consists of hundreds of award-winning titles from around the world including Connect.com, connect.co.uk, CIO, CSO, Game Pro, Network World, Macworld and PC World. The IDG Publishing Network is a growing collection of IDG web sites that presently includes cio.com, csoonline.com, infoworld.com, idgconnect.com, networkworld.com, macworld.com, pcworld.com and gamepro.com. A complete listing is available at [www.idg.com](http://www.idg.com/?utm_content=web.archive.org). The IDG Publishing Network is operated by our ultimate holding company International Data Group, Inc. together with its subsidiaries (“our Group”).

## The Purpose of this Policy - Your Consent

Respecting the privacy of our customers and ensuring the confidentiality of customer information is critical to IDG UK. The purpose of this Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) is to ensure that we interact with all of our customers in line with current legislation (such as the UK Data Protection Act 1998 and the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003) and in accordance with their wishes.  This Policy sets out below what types of personal data may be collected about you, how we may process and use it, and who we may share it with.

By using this Website and/ or submitting your personal data, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing activities described in this Policy. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this Policy.

## Personal Details

IDG UK and its suppliers may collect, process and use your personal data (including your name, postal address, email address, telephone, mobile and fax numbers). We will do so to contact you regarding the services you have requested and/or to offer services to you, and/or to provide the services you have requested. This includes re-registration/renewal notifications, payment processing, surveys on improving our service to you and/or invitations to exhibitions, seminars and shows. IDG UK may employ trusted third party specialists to process your data on our behalf in order to deliver the products and services to you in a more efficient manner.

This personal data is stored on IDG UK computers in the UK, and, because IDG UK is part of the IDG Publishing Network, may be transferred to, stored and processed, inside the UK and/or outside of the European Economic Area (“EEA”) by other members of our Group. In addition, if you consent to receive offerings from third party organisations, this personal data remains with IDG UK who will send the third party offerings.  Except as set forth below with regard to the provision of free resources, at no time will your personal data be transferred to such third party organisations.  Finally, as stated above, your personal data may be transferred to and stored by third party specialists engaged by IDG to assist in the provision of the content and services you request. Such vendors may be located inside or outside of the EEA. In all cases, we will only transfer your data outside the EEA to those countries that ensure at least adequate levels of protection for the rights and freedoms of data subjects in relation to the processing of personal data.

From time to time IDG UK and/or the IDG Publishing Network may invite you to register in order to receive such offerings as magazines, email newsletters, enter competitions, and receive goods or services from IDG UK and/or the IDG Publishing Network websites. This may require you to confirm personal data such as your name, email address, and mailing address postcodes. This information is mandatory and is required by IDG UK for security purposes, and enables IDG UK to supply a reasonable level of services to users and our advertisers.  We may also ask for information such as job function, job title, industry sector, company/ name and country. During registration, you will also be asked to choose a user name and password for future access to the relevant Website(s).

In order to provide you with free resources such as white papers and expert analysis, we may share your personal data and/or business information with third party organisations we partner with and whose content and/or other offerings you choose to view via an email offer we may send to you via Connect.com and/or connect.co.uk, and/or download from the PC Advisor Website or other IDG Publishing Network sites.

Because IDG UK is part of the IDG Publishing Network, you may receive offers that IDG UK believes will be of interest to you from any of the IDG Publishing Network sites.  However, IDG UK offers you the chance to opt out of receiving additional information from the IDG Publishing Network and our Group. You have the absolute right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. Whilst we give details in this Policy in relation to opting out, we want to make clear that you can at any time exercise this right by contacting us by post or email at the address set out at the foot of this Policy.

## Opting in/ Opting out

IDG offers you the opportunity to opt in to receive marketing information from carefully selected third party organisations. IDG UK will ensure that the contact you receive will be from reputable organisations. You may opt out at any time from receiving further such information by notifying us by post. IDG UK offers you the opportunity to opt out of receiving information from IDG UK about other products/services that IDG UK and our Group offer.

IDG cannot accept any responsibility for use by third parties of data that you have consented to being passed on.

## Disclosure of Information

If the business of operating this Website is sold, the relevant customer lists and other personal data of our subscribers and users will be transferred to the new owner. This will be done in accordance with current legislation.

We may disclose your personal data if we are under a duty to disclose your personal data as a result of a court order or any other legal obligation, any subpoena or legal process or as otherwise required by law, or if we believe it necessary to prevent or take action regarding illegal activities or violations of our policies.

## Changing your details and unsubscribing

At all times as a recipient of an IDG UK product and/or service or an IDG Publishing Network product and/or service you will have the opportunity to amend your contact details and/or to modify your opt-in/opt-out choices. We will not actually delete your record from the applicable database(s) as we would no longer be able to identify you, which could lead to you receiving information from us in the future. To action any of these requests please contact the relevant customer care department of the product/service you subscribe to.   
If you submit your email address to sign up for any of our online offerings including our newsletter(s) on the website, then you can unsubscribe at any time by either contacting, as applicable, IDG UK and/or the IDG Publishing Network directly or via the unsubscribe facility included in communications sent to you.

## Access to Information

You have the right to be told what personal data we hold about you on our databases. You should write to Ms Alex Lincoln, IDG Communications Ltd, 101 Euston Rd, London, NW1 2RA, United Kingdom. In your letter please state your full name, your address and all publications and/or services from IDG UK to which you know you subscribe. A small administration charge of £5.00 will be made for fulfilling this request.  

## Anonymous information about your use of the Website

In order that we can monitor and improve the Website, we may gather certain information about you when you use it, including details of your domain name and IP address, operating system, browser, version, cookie details (see below) and the website that you visited prior to our Website. IDG UK may make anonymous use of this information to help diagnose faults, manage our systems and gather broad demographic information about our users in general. This information will be stripped of all details that could identify you personally.   

## Other Links

Please be aware that our Website may link to other web sites which may be accessed through our Website. This statement does not extend to sites that are linked to IDG UK sites. You should refer to those sites for further details about their use of your personal information. We are not responsible for the data policies, content or security of these linked web sites.

## Cookies

For information on what cookies we use on IDG UK websites and how to manage them, [click here](http://www.idg.co.uk/cookies/?utm_content=web.archive.org).

## Changes to the Policy

IDG UK reviews its privacy and data protection policy periodically. We reserve the right to modify our privacy and data protection policy at any time without notice. Any changes to the policy will be posted on this page.

## Contact Us

If you have any comments or queries in connection with our privacy policy, please [Contact Us](mailto:Alex_lincoln@idg.co.uk?utm_content=web.archive.org).

We can be contacted at:   
IDG Communications Ltd  
101 Euston Road  
London  
NW1 2RA  
United Kingdom  
 **Phone:** +44 (0) 20 7756 2800  
 **Email:**[webmaster@idg.co.uk](mailto:webmaster@idg.co.uk?utm_content=web.archive.org)  
Last updated: May 09
